Edgecliff College records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Edgecliff College records
1936-1982
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Edgecliff College
5 linear feet (9 boxes)
This is a collection of selected records from Edgecliff College (Cincinnati, Ohio). These records reflect some college activities and the campus environment prior to the acquisition of the Edgecliff property by Xavier University.
XUA-37
History of Edgecliff College
Our Lady of Cincinnati College was founded in 1935 by the Sisters of Mercy as a women's college. In 1970 the college became co-educational and assumed the name Edgecliff College. Later, Xavier University acquired the Edgecliff campus and its academic programs.
Originally called Our Lady of Cincinnati College at its founding in 1935 by the Sisters of Mercy, the college educated young women exclusively until 1970 when it opened its classrooms to men and adopted a new name ... Edgecliff College. On July 1, 1980 Xavier University announced that it had purchased from the Sisters of Mercy a three year option to buy the Edgecliff campus property by June 30, 1983. Edgecliff College then became known as Edgecliff College of Xavier University, the fourth undergraduate college at Xavier University. In the Spring of 1983 Xavier completed the purchase of the Edgecliff property from the Sisters of Mercy. In April, 1987 Xavier University sold the Edgecliff property. Academic programming was transferred to the main Xavier campus that year. Edgecliff's departments of art, music, and theatre arts joined the College of Arts and Sciences, while its departments of nursing and social work were incorporated into Xavier's new College of Professional Studies.
Scope and Content
This is a collection of various documents relating to Edgecliff College and its former name of Our Lady of Cincinnati College. The holdings are limited.
Not specified
Statement of Arrangement
Materials are arranged into four main topics:
Institutional records, mainly faculty lists and handbooks
Edgecliff Long Range Planning Committee records and institutional surveys/data
Student related materials: Orientation, housing, committee records
Music Department scrapbook and photographs
Related Material
Xavier University Archives also has materials pertaining to the purchase and sale of the Edgecliff College property as well as various records relating to the transition of Edgecliff College programs to Xavier University. Please contact the Xavier Archives staff.
Restrictions on Access
Restricted access. Please contact the Xavier University Archives staff.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Edgecliff College--Students; Edgecliff College--Libraries; Edgecliff College--Planning; Edgecliff College. Music Department; Edgecliff College--Faculty; Edgecliff College--Student housing
Material Types:
Scrapbooks
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Administrative Records, including Faculty Lists and Handbooks, and Brennan Library, 1951-1997
  - Our Lady of Cincinnati. Office of the Registrar Student/Faculty Statistical Information, 1951-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Edgecliff College Faculty Lists, 1964-1965; 1974-1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Nursing Department Faculty List, 1975-1981, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Handbooks, 1960; undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Handbooks, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Commencement Programs, 1969; 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Course Information Pamphlets, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Grant Proposal: S & W Foundation Lectureship Program, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cooperation Memorandum Our Lady of Cincinnati/ Xavier University, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Edgecliff College Certificate of Authorization Ohio Board of Regents, 1978 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Brennan Memorial Library Acquisitions/ Inventory, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Brennan Memorial Library Policies, 1973-1979; undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Brennan Memorial Library Library Statistical Reports, 1957-1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Brennan Memorial Library Educational Media Center, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Brennan Memorial Library Grants Correspondence, 1958-1967; undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Brennan Memorial Library Student Library Manuals and Information, 1963-1977; undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Brennan Memorial Library Annual Reports, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Brennan Memorial Library Librarian Correspondence, 1968-1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Long Range Planning Committee and Institutional Surveys/Data, 1952-1979
  - Long Range Planning Committee Records, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Long Range Planning Committee Records, 1973-1977; undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Long Range Planning Committee Records Proposed Long Range Plan, 1976 November (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Title III Grant Planning, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Our Lady of Cincinnati College Survey of Student Personnel Services, 1952 June 11 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Our Lady of Cincinnati College Self-Study, 1952 June (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Edgecliff College Basic Institutional Data, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Edgecliff College Department of Education Report to Ohio Department of Education, 1976 November 17 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Edgecliff College Self-Study, 1979 December (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Student Related Materials: Orientation, Housing, Committee Records; Various Other Topics, 1936; 1940; 1953-1987
  - Co-Ed Housing Questionnaires, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Student Handbooks, 1953-1987 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Student Orientation Booklets, 1968-1980 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Student Residence Handbooks: Sullivan Hall, 1964-1985; undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Student Residence Handbooks: Emery, Harrison and Calendars, 1953-1979; undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Sullivan Hall Information Packets, 1964-1972 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Sullivan Hall Information Packets, 1972-1976 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Sullivan Hall Information Packets, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Sullivan Hall Information Packets, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Sullivan Hall Information Packets, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Sullivan Hall Information Packets, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Sullivan Hall Information Packets, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Sullivan Hall Information and Regulations Summer School and Retreats, 1964-1973 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Summer School Regulations, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Student Regulations Summer, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Dorm Council, 1968-1969; undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Dorm Council, 1969-1970; undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Questionnaires: Residence Halls; Dress, 1969; undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Committee on Student Affairs, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Committee on Student Affairs: Minutes, Correspondence, Questionnaire, 1970-1972 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Student Government Constitution, 1979 September 12 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Edgecliff Alumni: Brochure, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - First Edgecliff Graduate: Adele Pohl Photograph, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Assorted Publications, 1954-1982 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Our Lady of Cincinnati Prayer Cards, 1960-1983 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Our Lady of Cincinnati College Booklet, circa 1940 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Edgecliff College Descriptive Information Admissions Office, c. 1975-1980 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Building Brochures: Emery and Maxwelton Campus Map, 1973; undated (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Edgecliff College Postcards and Decals, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 56)
- Music Department Scrapbook and Photographs, 1935-1973; undated
  - Music Department Scrapbook, 1935-1973 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Music Department Scrapbook: Loose Inserts, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Music Department Scrapbook: Loose Inserts, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Music Department Scrapbook: Loose Inserts, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Music Department Scrapbook: Loose Inserts, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Music Department Scrapbook: Loose Inserts, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Music Department Scrapbook: Loose Inserts, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Music Department Scrapbook: Loose Inserts, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Music Department Scrapbook: Loose Inserts, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Music Department Scrapbook: Loose Inserts, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Music Department Scrapbook: Loose Inserts, Undated (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Musica Sacra City Proclamation, Undated (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Our Lady of Cincinnati College Incorporation Certification, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Photographs: Concerts, 1958; undated (Box 9, Folder 70)